What's going on guys? We're on the way right now
to meet up with John Abraham, who's a startup founder.
He started and sold a company a few years back, and
he's back in the game founding another tech startup right now.
So we're going to ask him some questions on how
he was able to start, grow, and eventually sell his businesses,
and what he implemented to make him successful.
Hey James. What's going on John? How you doing?
Good, good. Good to see you. Come
on in. Hey. Good to see you.
Good to see you.
We launched our application in 2014
and had an exit in 2018.
And now I'm working on a new startup called Haymaker.
What is the most efficient way to go
about raising capital to fund people's ideas and businesses?
As a business owner, what's the number one thing that you took
from starting and selling that first company to your second company now?
Oh gosh.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
I've since retired. I was in
tech sales for about 15, 20 years.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
It's a lot of money because I got stock options.
It was in the multi-million dollars of earnings in a
single year because I cashed out a whole bunch of stock.
Wow. Would you say eight figures?
Yeah, eight figures.
Eight figures.
What does it take to go from a
seven to eight figure net worth in today's world?
Well, I think if you really want to make that kind of money,
you got to find a company that is willing to invest in you,
or you got to go build your own business.
So investing in you would be giving you ownership in the
company so that you're going out there and you're selling hard,
but you're selling for the long term.
Or you got to find your own business.
You got to go learn early and take your learnings and
go do a business of your own from what you've learned.
That's something, what I know now, I
would have spent more time thinking about.
How do I take all my knowledge and instead
of doing it for someone else, do it for myself?
But only after you've built that base of knowledge.
Be confident and be fearless.
And then you need to go for it.
Excuse me, sir.
I just need to ask you a question.
If you had to start over at the back of the business,
if you were first starting out, what advice would you give yourself?
Thank you anyway.
No worries, sir.
Excuse me, sir.
Quick question for you.
If you were to start from zero and go back
to when you were first starting out in the real world,
what's the best advice that you would tell yourself?
You guys were here last time.
Yes, sir.
So as you can see,
rejection is part of the process.
We get a lot of funny rejections, a lot
of stuff you don't even see behind the scenes.
I got to ask you, what's
the worst rejection you've ever had?
Man, the worst rejection, there's been a lot of them.
I think one of them was
when we were in San Antonio.
We were kind of at like a shopping center.
I went up to a
gentleman and asked him, you know,
hey, could we do a quick interview with you?
And he just kind of gave me
the most staunch hand in the face.
He's like, get that fucking camera out of my face.
It happens, man.
It's going to happen.
The worst ones, they don't even say anything.
They just put the hand up, and
you just know to just keep it moving.
But at the end of the day, as we
always know, every no is closer to a yes.
So we just keep going.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
I consult with governments around the
country, with a lot of cities,
mostly local governments, on specific issues
that governments are facing these days.
And what has been the most amount of
money that you ever made in a single year?
I worked in government.
So I never made a whole lot of money.
But being out on my own now, probably
close to a half a million dollars a year.
Absolutely.
What would you say is the number one skill
that's needed to be successful in the business world?
I think to become truly successful, I think
you have to have that magic connection between assertiveness,
truly trying to assert yourself, to
get out of your comfort zone,
to try things that you haven't tried before.
It's not just about diligence and focus.
It's really just about trying new things.
And at the same time, professionalism, follow through,
viewing those relationships truly
as relationships and not networking.
It's not a transactional life.
It's building relationships that you're going to
grow throughout the rest of your life.
I surround myself with large networks of people, and I
pull them all the time about the things I'm doing.
I talk to people about what I'm up to and
making sure you have good people who are supporting you,
who are kind and who are charitable.
That's important.
So we don't typically run into a
lot of government employees down here in Austin,
but it's really interesting his story, how he
worked for the government, became a business consultant.
Now he's got his own business, but loved his advice.
And let's go catch some more.
What was the most amount of money
you ever made in a single year?
What industry did you pursue a career in?
I built jail cells.
What is the blueprint that it takes
to become a millionaire in today's world?
I always was interested in a
niche industry, which I am certainly in,
because in New England, there's nobody
else that does what I do.
So find a niche, work hard, get the right people.
I don't see how you could not be successful.
When you see an opportunity, take advantage of it.
If it's not working out, get out
fast or pursue it right to the end.
I've done that multiple times,
and it's worked out pretty well.
And I've also had, I went in one direction.
I added a component to my company.
It didn't work out.
Cut ties, gone.
You lose a little money, but in the long run,
you lose a lot less than if you stay with it.
A few weeks ago, we ran into and met
a startup founder out here in Austin, Texas, who sold
a company a few years ago and is
now in the process of building another tech startup.
Now the story of how we actually
ran into him was kind of funny.
Yeah, so we're at a Mexican restaurant called
Puevos, and we're sitting next to this two
people.
It's John and this other lady,
and we overhear them talking about business.
So we're like, hey, James, I
think these guys are business owners.
Let's just go ask them.
Let's ask them what they do
and kind of like who they are.
And so we go ahead,
we ask them who they are.
And we found out that this guy, John
Abraham, he's actually a startup founder in Austin,
Texas, who previously sold a company, is in
the process of building a new company, and
he's in the process of
scaling and growing it right now.
And so we said, hey, this is what we do.
We connect with, we interview, we tell stories
from big business owners and try to get their
advice on how they became successful to
help the younger generation of people that are
out in the real world really become successful like them.
So we actually just talked to him recently,
and he said that, hey, let's film some more
content.
Let's give you guys some game on how
you can really start, scale, grow a business to
eventually be sold.
So we're going to go talk to
John Abraham now on how he became successful.
Hey, James.
What's going on, John?
How you doing?
Good, good.
Good to see you.
Come on in.
Hey.
Good to see you.
What is your story as a startup founder and
entrepreneur, and what all are you up to right
now?
I used to bartend in college, and a lot
of folks would come in from Dell and from Applied
Materials and Intel.
And I knew I wanted in
on that, on the tech space.
And so I finally begged one of them into giving
me a chance at sales, and that's how I started
my sales career in tech.
We launched our application in 2014
and had an exit in 2018.
And now I'm working on a new
startup called Haymaker, which is like Airbnb.
It's a marketplace, but except it's
for on-demand and temporary office space.
A lot of people have a lot of great ideas.
What's the first step in order to turn
that idea to actual action, execute on that?
Well.
Before you create anything, you need to understand
the viability of the product and the total
addressable market.
So before you build anything, I would
start with interviewing as many potential clients
as you can.
If you've recognized a need in some sort
of industry or some space, you want to start
with talking to the decision makers in that space.
What are your challenges?
What are you struggling with?
And the more interviews, the better.
And then go back to them and say, if
we can solve this problem for you, what would that
mean for your company?
You're not quite asking for a sale yet.
You're just trying to get them to help you.
You understand what would that mean for them.
And then if you can get somebody to
commit to piloting that project early on, then you
can go and build your MVP, your minimally viable product.
That is the best approach.
Yeah.
And I kind of wanted to ask you.
So you have that idea.
You start to kind of get a team around it.
You start to invest some money in it.
At what point do you know that you have
a good idea and that you should keep investing
in it?
You don't until you figure
out a way to scale it.
It could solve a really substantial problem, but
until you figure out how to get customers,
you don't really have a great idea.
Yeah.
What is your best piece of advice
for entrepreneurs that might be struggling with
perfectionism?
They're constantly in an analysis paralysis,
working on their product, and they're not
sending it out into the market.
What would be your piece of advice for those entrepreneurs?
I've maybe been guilty of this myself, but
I think perfectionism is really a form of
insecurity.
So you don't want anybody calling the baby
ugly, so you're never going to show anybody
the baby.
That's not a place where you can
really get any constructive feedback and course correct
if you need to.
If you have a differentiator though that you can highlight.
and then let your client buy in on helping you
shape the product in a way that's maybe a better
fit for them, now they're bought in. So it's
a great opportunity for you to just show them
something. You know it's not perfect. You even admit
it's not perfect. What can we do to make
this perfect for you? It's very common to face
a lot of failure on your journey as an entrepreneur.
But what is your advice to someone who
is facing that failure maybe frequently as an entrepreneur?
And how can you really overcome that
adversity and those setbacks? Well, adversity and setbacks
are part of the journey. And the journey is really
what you should be in it for if you decide
to become an entrepreneur. It's not the destination. I
know we celebrate the money that comes with an
exit or an IPO. But the thing that really
changes you and the thing that will help your mindset
through this journey is if you can realize that
those are the things that will shape you into a
really successful person who can overcome obstacles
down the road, who can meet challenges head-on,
who can help other people who
are going through those challenges. That's
the journey.
Really the point of the entire journey. So
one of the biggest struggles that business owners face
is raising capital to fund their great ideas that
they may have. What is the most efficient way to
go about raising capital to fund people's ideas
and businesses? But if you're just getting started,
it is a lot cheaper now to build a product
and test your product. Once you get that step done,
hopefully you're generating some revenue where you
can keep investing back into the business,
build it out broader and broader, build traction, then
take it out for investment. There is no magic
number that you need to get to.
But you just need to show that there's potential,
there's repeatable customer acquisition. You have a plan for that.
And ideally, you're moving up with
your revenue and your MRR every month.
What is the number one important thing that you can
implement to scale your business from six to seven figures,
from seven to eight, and
maybe eventually eight to nine figures?
The rule that I use is, one, if I could outsource
this for less than my hourly rate, then I'm going to outsource.
If it means bringing on someone permanent, that's something that
you'll just have to budget for and build your forecast.
And if you're going to do that, you're going to have
to build your forecast on and continue to bring people on.
What do you think is the absolute best
way to go about marketing your product or service?
If you're an enterprise play and you
have enterprise clients, there's one strategy there.
Email is actually still pretty prolific there, but it's going
to be a mix, you know, a mix of social
media. It's going to be a mix of direct
outreach through emails. It might even be cold calling if
you're doing enterprise stuff. If you're doing more
of a consumer play, gosh, social media plays a
pretty critical role there.
You built and sold a company in 2018.
What does that process look like of selling a company and
how can you set up your company to be sold one day?
Best way to set up your company to be
sold is just to keep focusing on the bottom line.
Keep building revenue, keep moving the needle. And if
you keep doing it and it's efficient, people notice.
Institutional investors will notice. They probably want to,
you know, help you along and help promote
the company in the form of an investment
or an acquisition might take place. And, you know,
because they want to be part of that or they
want to roll your products into their services and offerings.
And that happens every day.
One of the things you mentioned is having
that circle around you, that board of advisors.
How important do you think it is to have a
mentor and just that whatever advisors around you to give
you that proper advice and guiding
to where you really need to go?
There's typically not one person that you go
to for everything. You might have that one person
that you go to to keep you motivated, like
a business coach or some sort of motivational coach
or something like that. But there's a lot of nuance
to running a business and you're not going to be
an expert at everything. So if possible, go out
and try to find people who are experts in
those categories. I still have sales mentors.
I can't, you forget, you get rusty sometimes.
And so you got to, you know, you got to
go out and go back to your mentors and they'll steer
you down the right ship.
So the company you're currently building right now
is called Haymaker. Can you tell us a little
bit about that and what you're
up to as the owner of it?
Yeah. Haymaker is an online marketplace similar
to Airbnb, but we specialize in temporary office
and meeting spaces. This is actually one of
our Haymaker spaces here. It's ideal for companies
with distributed employees that don't
have a ton of office space.
To supplement that office space. So we have
luxury homes like this one. We have flex spaces,
studios, traditional commercial real estate. They're all
available by the hour or by the day.
What made you come up with this idea?
Oh gosh. During the pandemic, actually
pre-pandemic, my co-founder came up with the
idea of launching more of an online marketplace
for coworking. But then when the pandemic hit,
we saw the number of people moving around
and that really affirmed that we're headed down the
right path. Pivoted a little bit from
just coworking into meeting spaces since so many
companies had dropped their real estate footprints or
could just no longer justify carrying as much
space as they had. John, thank you so much
for having us out to your spot. We really enjoyed
getting to talk to you today. Where can everybody
find you and find out more about your company?
Yeah. You can come to haymakerspace.com, check it
out, look at our listings there. You can book
directly through our app as well, which you can
link to from the website. I'm also on LinkedIn,
John Abraham. And if you guys want to learn
more about how you can start and grow your
first business, click this link right here.